Claire Cashmore

Computer/Software Engineer

clairecashmore2017@gmail.com (928)-853-6171 Alexandria, VA



www.linkedin.com/in/claire-cashmore/

https://clairecashmore17.github.io/claire-cashmore-

portfolio/



https://github.com/clairecashmore17

Overview

Software Engineer eager to work in a fast-paced environment. Looking to exhibit my web development skills and contribute to a team with communication, teamwork, and self-disciplined abilities. 5 years of experience with software practices. Successful Dean's list student.

Skills

- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Microprocessors
- C++, C, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Node.js, Express.js, React
- MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose

Work Experience

Full Stack Development (Freelance)

September 2022- Present Alexandria, VA/Remote

- Designated as head software developer
- Develop website showcasing Crochet Creations for Morgans Marvelous Makes.
- Implement MongoDB, and Express for the backend assisted with Javascript, HTML, CSS, and React for the frontend.

Peer tutoring (Self-Employed)

May 2021- Present Alexandria, VA/Remote

- Successfully tutored all students to pass course.
- Assisted peers in gaining basic coding practices to complete their coursework.
- Study 2–3-hour sessions twice a week
- Encouraged confidence in problem solving by themselves with a directional input.
- 1:1 discussion tailored to help individuals learn in their specific learning style.

Head Coach (Soccer Shots)

August 2021 – November 2021 Front Royal, VA

- Promoted to head coach within 1 week of employment.
- Instructed children ages 2-4 to develop basic soccer and social skills.

Education

Certificate

GWU 2U Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp

May 2022 – October 2022

Remote

B.S Computer Engineering

Embry Riddle Aeronautical University, Prescott Campus

August 2017-May 2021

Prescott, AZ

GPA: 3.471

Projects

Movie Matchers https://github.com/clairecashmore17/project-1 Deployment: https://clairecashmore17.github.io/project-1/

- Developed front-end application using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.
- Use the DOM to dynamically alter page with user interaction
- Utilizes localStorage to allow users to save their favorite movie and beverage combos.
- Deployed with Github Pages

Bragging Rights https://github.com/clairecashmore17/bragging-rights Deployment: https://aqueous-stream-06315.herokuapp.com/

- Developed full-stack application using JavaScript, HTML, CSS for the front end accompanied with Node.js, Express.js, and MySQL for the backend.
- Includes user authentication for login, allowing access to personalized information
- Users can interact with and create posts on their favorite game achievements.
- Deployed using Heroku App.

Web Browser Game using Phaser and React https://github.com/clairecashmore17/phaser-game

- Developed a web browser game using React and Phaser.
- Created using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Phaser, Node.js.
- Users can move character around on screen and interact with other objects.

Senior Design Capstone Project (FireWatch)

- Design a transparent OLED screen that depicted the distance and location of the familial devices on an LED screen. Implemented a Berry GPS unit, XBEE module, and Raspberry Pi Zero. Used SPI communication
- 2nd Lead

Profile Generator https://github.com/clairecashmore17/profile-generator

- Developed Full Stack using OOP.
- JavaScript, HTML, and CSS, Node.js.
- Utilizes Inquirer to gather information and store as objects.
- Creates webpage with generated team profiles
- Utilizes Jest for testing/debugging.